♪ As the sun goes down ♪
♪ And the shadows grow long ♪
♪ Trying to find a gal I can call my own ♪
♪ Gettin' back on the road, not a moment too soon... ♪
Marta阿姨7点会准时到家
Aunt Marta's gonna be at the house 7:00 sharp,
所以你最好做好准备
so you best be ready.
你上学不能迟到
You can't be late for school
她上班也不能迟到
and she can't be late for work.
不行 你不能和那个男孩结伴回家
No, you cannot walk home with that boy.
我们已经讨论过了
We've had this conversation.
他很讨人厌
He's bad news.
不行
No.
生活中要我担心的事已经够多的了
I have enough things in my life to worry about
除了不担心
without having to worry about...
NCIS 新奥尔良
S03E15
可以了 小心点
Okay, easy now.
任何时候 你想要歇一会的话
Anytime you, uh, you want to take a break,
CJ　只要　告诉我就好
CJ, you know, just... just let me know, okay?
不用了　我没事　你还好吗
No, I'm good. You okay?
还好　我现在是NCIS的探员了　这个
Yeah, I'm an NCIS agent now. This is, you know...
这个小菜一碟
this is a piece of cake.
还是把它放下吧
Let's set it down.
好主意
Yeah, that's a great idea.
-我只是有点好奇　-嗯
-　Just out of curiosity...　- Huh?
你怎么会又一次顺利通过基础训练的呢
how'd you make it through basic training again?
那个
That's...
得通过学习和努力
Got through from studying and effort,
这两样你都能用得上
both of which you could use a little more of.
我只是想要帮忙 妈
I'm just trying to help, Mom.
你只不过是想要Danny的房间罢了 因为他现在走了
Only 'cause you want Danny's room now that he's gone.
说到学习 明天就要数学考试了
Back to studying, Math test tomorrow.
去吧
Go.
再见 菜鸟
See you, newbie.
我真不敢相信他这么快就长大了
I can't believe how fast he's growing up, you know?
我也不敢相信我的孩子们这么快就都长大了
I can't believe how fast all my boys are growing up.
Danny加入海军了 你在NCIS
Danny joining the Navy, you at NCIS...
谢谢 医生 我和你的感觉一样
Oh, thanks, Doc, you know I feel the same about you.
你就像是我从未有过的母亲一样
You're like the mother that I never had.
你有母亲 Sebastian
You have a mother, Sebastian.
我见过她
I've met her.
确实
Exactly.
所以 这就变成了Wade之家吗
So, what, this gonna be the Wade cave now?
60英寸的等离子电视吗
Hmm? 60-inch plasma maybe?
扑克桌 熔岩灯吗
Poker table, a couple lava lamps?
我想弄成艺术工作室
I was thinking art studio, actually.
在我结婚前我一直在画画
I used to paint all the time before I got married.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, hold on.
我从不知道你结过婚
I never knew you were married.
结过 很久以前 不一样的生活
Yes, I was. A long time ago, different life.
你来看看
Have a look for yourself.
是他吗
Is this him?
Reginald
Reginald.
他挺好看的 是吧
Easy on the eye, isn't he?
是啊 那时你看上去真漂亮
Yeah, look how beautiful you were.
那种 不是说你现在不漂亮
That's... um, not that you're not beautiful now.
显然 你很 漂亮 只是
Obviously, you're... you're very beautiful, it's just...
你懂得 当你
you know, when you...
没关系 Sebastian
It's all right, Sebastian.
我们初遇时 Reginald是个很好的人
Reginald was a good man when we first met.
曾经我们也有过几年好时光
We had some good years together...
直到我们分开
until we didn't.
发生什么了
What happened?
我只能说他变了
Let's just say he changed...
不是往好的方向转变
not for the better.
来任务了
Duty calls.
看来我有具尸体要检验
Looks like I've got a body.
NCIS 可能是同一具
Yeah, NCIS. It's probably the same body.
你要和我拼车吗
You want to share a ride?
只要你不继续追问
Only if you don't ask any more questions.
这些人会照顾你的
These guys'll take care of you.
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
是她发现的案发现场吗
She the first on scene?
有轨电车司机 刚要上班
Streetcar driver, just showing up for work.
新的一天没有好的开始
Not the best way to start a day.
大概和案件一样恐怖
About as grisly as it gets.
有目击者吗
Any witnesses?
新奥尔良警局说没有
Not according to NOPD,
希望我们能在监控录像里有所发现
but hopefully we got something from these security cameras.
我很怀疑
Well, I doubt it.
凶手把尸体
Killer placed the body
直接摆在这些有轨电车后面
directly behind these streetcars,
挡住了所有摄像头
blocking all the cameras.
我很怀疑凶手曾试图避开摄像头
I doubt the killer was trying to avoid cameras.
地点过于明确
It's too specific of a location.
我的侧写认为 无论凶手是谁
Profiler in me seems to think that whoever it was
都想做一个声明
was trying to make a statement.
我打赌你不想再约她出去了 对不对
Take it you don't want to ask her out again, am I right?
相亲 高风险
Blind date, high risk.
我告诉过你 她们不值一顿正餐
I told you, they're not worth dinner.
只喝酒就好 而且你也绝不该把你的号码给她
Just drinks, and you definitely don't give your number
直到你确定你喜欢她
until you're sure you like her.
Gregorio 那是你的侧写吗
Is that you profiling, Gregorio?
那是我的约会观 外行人
That's me dating, amateur.
我有过好多次约会 我不是外行
Mm, I've dated plenty. I'm not an amateur.
也许能找几个炮友
Maybe a couple of hookups,
但是没可能发展成男女朋友关系
but not potential relationships.
这简直是完全不同的两码事
It's a whole different deal,
还有那些约会软件上修图过度的照片
and this whole airbrushed-photo thing on dating apps...
我是说 唯一能确定双方是否有感觉的方法
I mean, the only way to trigger the yay or nay hormones
就是良好的 老式的 眼神接触
is to have good, old-fashioned eye contact.
我从不知道你是个浪漫主义者 Gregorio
I never knew you as a romantic, Gregorio.
侧写不仅是为了找出罪犯
Profiling's not just for finding criminals.
生活中也很有用的 相信我
Comes in handy, trust me.
目前我只知道受害者是军士长Karen Decker
All I know so far is the victim's Chief Karen Decker,
驻扎在Belle Chasse
based out of Belle Chasse.
还在等Loretta
Still waiting on Loretta,
所以我们现在还不能把尸体放下来
so we can't take the body down yet.
地上没有很多血迹
Not a lot of blood on the ground,
身上有很多刺伤的伤口
considering all the stab wounds,
这说明她是在其他地方遇害
which means she was killed somewhere else,
然后被移到这里
and then moved here.
问题是 为什么移到这里
The question is, why here?
要冒很大的风险
Big risk...
把她吊起来既费时又费力
taking the time and effort to string her up,
更别提对尸体的损毁了
not to mention the mutilation.
是仪式行为么
Talking ritualistic?
十字架的姿势表明她应该是一个祭品
Crucifix pose indicates she was meant to be a sacrifice.
眼睛被挖走了所以她无法看见凶手的灵魂
Eyes dug out so she couldn't see her killer's soul.
行 那么 我们若搞清楚
Okay, so, we figure out
她为什么献祭
what she was sacrificed for,
也许就能确定是哪个疯子对她做了这样的事
we might be able to ID the lunatic who did this to her.
天啊
My God.
Loretta
Loretta.
Loretta 你还好吗
Loretta, you all right?
请把她放下来
Please, get her down.
我们去找个梯子吧
Let's go find a ladder.
听着 Gregorio
Look, Gregorio,
我会向Decker的指挥官了解情况 好吗
I'll check with Decker's C.O., all right?
你带上Christopher和Patton
You take Christopher and get with Patton,
尽快并尽可能多的了解关于她的信息
find out as much about her as you can as fast as you can.
遵命
Copy that.
真是难以直视 不是吗
Tough to look at, isn't it?
我之前见过类似的事情
I saw something like this once before.
我曾经希望再也别让我见到这样的事
I'd hoped never to see it again.
兄弟 真难想象有人会想伤害她
Man, hard to believe anybody would want to do her harm,
尤其是用这种方式
especially that kind of harm.
20年的老兵 无任何不良记录
20-year vet, unblemished record,
是海军法律顾问 为其他海军士兵提供帮助
Navy counselor who helps other sailors.
是啊 根据她的记录来看
Yeah, a couple of months from retiring,
她才退休几个月
according to her record.
正是要开始新生活的时候
About to start a new life.
可这一切都被一个恶魔毁了 为什么
Only to have it stolen away by some monster. Why?
指挥官说 Decker军士长昨天中午接到了一通紧急电话
C.O. says Chief Decker got an urgent call yesterday at noon,
急忙出去了 再也没回来
rushed out, never came back.
查一下她的电话记录
Check her phone log?
放到大屏幕上了
Putting it up on the screen.
看起来昨天只有一通打进来的电话
Looks like the only incoming call she got yesterday.
但是和几天前打来电话的是同一个人
But from the same caller who called several days before.
你能追查到那个家伙吗
Can you trace that joker?
不能 这是一次性手机
Can't, burner cell.
而且处于关机状态 或者更有可能的是 手机已被毁坏了
Powered down, too. Or, more likely, destroyed.
好吧 还有什么其它方法可以找出电话是从哪打来的吗
Well, any chance you can find out where the call originated?
正在想办法 老大
Read my mind, bossman.
在这儿 信号是从Peters中学的
There, pinged from a cell tower
手机信号塔发射出来的
across from the old Peters Junior High School.
现在 这所学校在卡特琳娜飓风后就被废弃了
Now, Peters has been abandoned since Katrina,
谁会在那里出没呢
and who would want to be hanging there?
很显然 是某个
Obviously, somebody who doesn't
不想被发现的人 我们可以行动了吗
want to be found. Shall we?
有发现通知我 我要去停尸房
Keep me posted. I'm gonna go to the morgue.
看看Loretta发现了什么
See what Loretta knows.
坏消息
Bad news.
见鬼 Sebastian 别那样鬼鬼祟祟地靠近我
Damn it, Sebastian! Don't sneak upon me like that.
喔 喔 抱歉 抱歉
Whoa, whoa, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
你 你还好吗
Are-Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
呃 只是
Uh, it's just...
呃
Uh...
你有发现什么吗
You got something?
很不走运 没有
Um, u-unfortunately, no.
现场没能发现任何有用的线索
There's nothing from the crime scene that turned up any clues.
没有指纹 可追踪的证据 DNA 什么都没有
No prints, trace evidence, DNA, nothing.
凶手很显然知道他在做什么
Whoever did this obviously knows what they're doing.
你想让我再试试吗
You want me to keep trying?
NCIS暂时可能不需要我回去
NCIS probably doesn't need me back for a while.
玻璃盘
Glass tray.
这是什么
What is it?
我是说 很显然 这是一缕头发 但是
I mean, clearly, it's a strand of hair, but...?
我在被害人头发里找到的
I found it in the victim's hair.
但不是她的
It's not hers.
很有可能是凶手的
Could be the killer's.
如果我没猜错
And, if I'm right,
我和凶手曾经有过交集
I've crossed paths with him before.
哟 我可不是吹牛 说到做媒 我可是业绩惊人
Yo, I'm not bragging, but I got a pretty good track record
不是为我自己 这点你可记住了
when it comes to matchmaking, just not for myself, mind you,
那可是个完全不同的故事了
that's a whole different story.
为什么这么说
Well, why is that?
你知道的 原因很复杂
You know, it's just complicated.
看上去我们刚和某人擦肩而过
Looks like we just missed somebody.
“Jack Gordon 氯氮平”
“Jack Gordon. Clozapine”
氯氮平
Clozapine?
是治疗精神病的药吗 精神分裂症
Is that for psychosis? Schizophrenia?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
看上去我们找到Decker军士长是在哪里遇害的了
Looks like we've found where Chief Decker was murdered.
也意味着我们找到作案的恶魔
Which means we've found our monster.
干得好 Christopher
Good job, Christopher.
保护现场 发布协查通告
Secure the scene, get a BOLO out.
我会让Sebastian过去搜集证据
I'll send Sebastian to collect evidence.
Loretta 我们可能找到
Loretta, we might have...
Loretta
Loretta.
可能找到嫌疑人了
Might have a suspect.
有前科 刚刚获得假释
Ex-con, just got paroled.
Jack Gordon
Jack Gordon.
是 你怎么知道的
Yeah. How'd you know?
20年前 我经手了他的案子
I worked the case
处理了他的首位被害人
on his first victim 20 years ago.
如果他这样做了
And, if he did this...
我很有可能就是下一个
...I could very well be next.
她还好吗
She all right?
不知道
Don't know.
坚强的女人
Tough lady.
我从没见过她这么慌乱过
I've never seen her rattled like this before.
告诉我你们的发现
Tell me things.
Jack Gordon
Jack Gordon,
又叫 “杰克刀”
aka “The Jackknife,”
20年前因谋杀入狱
paroled eight days ago from Angola after serving
八天前刚被假释出狱
just over 20 years for murder.
Loretta说他当时是电车司机 是吗
Loretta said he was a streetcar driver back in the day?
驾驶963路电车
Drove streetcar number 963,
Decker军士长被悬挂的尸体后面就是
the same streetcar Chief Decker's body
这路列车
was strung up behind.
很难相信这都是巧合
Hard to believe it's a coincidence.
是啊 加上我们在学校找到的血样
Yeah, plus the blood we found at the school
和Decker的完全吻合 这就意味着
is a dead match to Decker, which means...
Decker是在学校被杀的
Decker was killed at the school,
然后被转移到了电车那边
then moved to the streetcar.
这家伙才出狱不到一周时间
Guy's out of prison barely a week,
就立马锁定Decker
immediately targets Decker,
并且采用20年前同样的作案手法
and kills her the same way
杀害了Decker
he killed a woman 20 years ago.
士官Janet Ortega
Petty Officer Janet Ortega.
97年她和Decker在美国海军舰艇
She and Decker were bunkmates
服役时曾为室友
on the U.S.S. Enterprise in '97.
而且Ortega和Jack Gordon
And Ortega and Jack Gordon
在高中阶段曾是情侣
were high school sweethearts back then.
大概有情感纠葛
Some sweetheart.
没有明确的杀人动机 但能明显看出
Never proved motive, but it's got
这是激情犯罪
crime of passion written all over it.
是 我记得Ortega的案子
Yeah, well, I remember the Ortega case.
当时我是治安官 是新奥尔良警局处理的那个案子
NOPD handled it when I was a sheriff.
Gordon之所以有了绰号
Gordon got his nickname because
因为他的行凶武器是一把刀
the murder weapon was a knife.
Jack Gordon 杰克刀 真可爱
Jack Gordon, Jackknife, cute.
但是他为什么刚出狱没多久就杀掉Decker军士长呢
But why kill Chief Decker as soon as he gets out of prison?
而且让案情如此明显 他就是凶手
And make it so obvious that he did it?
我们需要从之前的老案子查起
Well, we need to dig into the old case,
但是如果我没记错的话
but if I remember right,
Decker军士长在审判Gordon的时候作了证
Chief Decker testified against Gordon at the trial,
称他是个情绪很不稳定的人
claimed he was unstable.
根据我们在学校找到的氯氮平的空瓶子来看
Well, based on the empty bottle of clozapine we found
他现在的情况更不稳定了
at the school, he's even more unstable now.
除此之外 他的DNA
Plus, his DNA
和法医在死者身上找到的
matched a strand of hair
一缕头发相吻合
Doc found on the victim.
这一切很明显 不是吗
Well, it's pretty clear, isn't it?
Gordon出了监狱 要向20年前
Gordon gets out of prison, takes out his revenge on Decker
指认他的Decker复仇
for testifying against him 20 years ago.
但问题是 根据Loretta所说
Problem is, according to Loretta,
20年前她也同样指认了Gordon
she testified against Gordon 20 years ago, too.
我就是当时负责Janet Ortega一案的法医
I was the M.E. on Janet Ortega's case.
作案手段实在是 残忍 令人作呕
The slaying was... brutal, sick.
当然 Gordon声称他是无辜的
Gordon claimed he was innocent, of course,
但是证据是无懈可击的
but the evidence was overwhelming.
Ortega的尸体显示出死前曾遭受过暴力侵害的迹象
Ortega's body showed signs of previous assaults.
他们在犯罪现场发现的刀属于Gordon
The knife they found at the crime scene belonged to Gordon,
他当时在安非他命的作用下昏昏沉沉
and he was so hopped up on amphetamines,
以至于他在被捕的时候
when they went to arrest him,
根本想不起来自己在谋杀案当晚
he couldn't even remember where he was
身在何处
the night of the murder.
安非他命性精神错乱
Amphetamine psychosis
确实可以解释那种程度的暴力行为
certainly could explain that level of violence.
没什么可以解释
Nothing explains what he did
他对那个可怜女人所做的一切
to that poor woman.
我一直没弄明白 为什么公诉人达成了协议
I just never understood why the prosecutor cut a deal.
她本应该置他于死地
She should've put that man away for life.
看看现在发生了什么
And now look what happened.
Dwayne 在他伤害到其他人以前
You've got to find him, Dwayne,
你一定要找到他
before he hurts anybody else.
我们会竭尽全力的 Loretta
We're gonna do everything we possibly can, Loretta.
不论如何 如果Gordon
Still, if Gordon
确实杀害了Decker军士长
did kill Chief Decker,
那他为什么在案发前给她打了那么多次电话
why did he call her so many times in the days before?
也许是嘲弄她
Taunting her, maybe?
是啊 但是 她为什么接受那些嘲弄呢
Yeah, but, why would she accept them?
为什么不直接挂掉然后报警呢
Why not just hang up and alert the NOPD instead?
他还没试着给你打电话 对吧
He hasn't tried calling you, has he?
-他不敢 -虽是如此
- He wouldn't dare. - Nevertheless,
如果 他确实把指证过他的人
if, in fact, he's targeting people
作为袭击目标的话 在找到他之前
who testified against him, we've got to protect you
我们必须保护你
until we find him.
我能照顾好我自己
I can take care of myself.
这次不行
Not this time, you can't.
在我们弄清到底发生什么之前
Until we know exactly what's going on,
对你而言 最安全的地方就是跟我们在一起
safest place for you is with us.
也就是说 CJ
Which means, CJ...
我跟Danny谈过了 CJ会和他一起待在基地
I spoke with Danny, and CJ's on base with his brother.
好的 很好
All right, well, good.
与此同时 我们需要查清
In the meantime, we need to find out
还有谁指证了Gordon并提醒他们
who else testified against Gordon, warn them.
你应该调查一下被告律师 Devon Mitchell
You should look into the defense attorney, Devon Mitchell.
我记得Gordon曾怪罪他没能让自己无罪释放
I remember Gordon blamed him for not getting him acquitted.
我们去找Mitchell吧
Let's find Mitchell.
Patton和我会尽量加快
Patton and I will get up to speed on the old case
调查老案子的进度
as quickly as possible.
试着找出相关线索 找到Gordon
Try to get leads on how to find Gordon.
-出发 -收到
- Go. - You got it.
-我们会找到他的 Loretta -好
- We'll find him, Loretta. - Yeah.
我保证
I promise.
有什么需要吗
Can I help you?
特别探员Lasalle和Gregorio
Special Agents Lasalle and Gregorio.
我们需要跟Mitchell先生谈谈
We need to speak to Mr. Mitchell, please.
哦 别担心 他没做错什么
Oh, don't worry, he hasn't done anything wrong.
但是我们确实需要跟他谈谈
But we do need to speak to him.
当然 我会告诉他
Of course. I'll let him know.
衷心感谢
Thank you kindly.
Mitchell先生
Mr. Mitchell...
那就是我说的那种眼神接触
That's exactly the eye contact I'm talking about.
明确的联系 毫无疑问
Clear connection, no doubt about it.
我不跟你讨论这个 Gregorio
I'm not doing this with you, Gregorio.
异性间的化学反应迅速而明显
The chemistry is immediately palpable,
你无法伪装 就连我都能感觉得到
you can't fake that; even I can feel it.
如果你不约她 我约
If you don't go for her, I will.
怎么了
What?
你们确定吗
Are you sure?
我是说 我都不知道Jack出狱了
I mean, I didn't even know that Jack was out.
他没试图联系你 给你打电话吗
He hasn't tried to contact you, or call you?
没 没有
No, nothing.
你们真的认为他杀害Karen Decker
You really think that he killed Karen Decker,
就因为她指证了他吗
just because she testified against him?
我们正试图查清这事
That's what we're trying
Mitchell先生 但是如果他真的这么做了
to find out, Mr. Mitchell, but if he did,
你的处境也会很危险
you could be in danger, too.
没错 我们听说Gordon对你格外不满
Yeah, we heard Gordon was particularly upset with you
因为你没能让他无罪释放
for not getting him acquitted.
我做了能做的一切
I did everything that I could.
我甚至无偿接手了这个案子
I even took the case pro Bono.
我是说 我认识Jack
I mean, I knew Jack.
他曾是有轨电车司机
He was the streetcar driver
我每天上班都坐他开的那趟车
who took me to work here every day.
我不想让他被警察缠住
I didn't want him to get stuck with a PD,
所以我主动提出为他辩护
so I offered to defend him.
所以审判之后你没再跟他谈过
So you haven't talked to him since the trial?
他在监狱的时候我给他打过电话
I called him in prison to check up on him,
但是他唯一希望我做的就是让案子重审
but all he ever wanted me to do was get the case reopened.
因为他仍坚信自己是无辜的吗
Because he still believed he was innocent?
他从来没有动摇过
He never stopped believing it.
这并不能改变案件的事实
Didn't change the facts of the case,
但Jack从未真正关心过事实
but Jack never really cared about facts.
听着 如果要算账的话 Jack欠我的
Look, if anything, Jack owes me.
我让地方检察官根据Jack的精神状态
I got the D.A. to agree to a reduced sentence
同意给他减了刑
based on Jack's mental state.
我是说 我救了他的命
I mean, I saved his life.
他为什么会追杀我
Why would he be after me?
我们不确定他在追杀你 Mitchell先生
We're not sure he is, Mr. Mitchell,
但是为了以防万一 我们会把你保护起来
but we're gonna get you protection just in case.
你还能不能记得什么人能帮我们
Is there anything you remember that might help us
找到Gordon 家人或者朋友
find Gordon? Family or friends?
我们尤其关心 还有没有其他人
Well, we're especially concerned about anybody else
可能会被Gordon追杀
Gordon might be after.
我们正在列一个单子
We're putting together a list, that...
呃 Todd Borger
Uh, Todd Borger.
Jack的朋友 开夜班车
Friend of Jack's, drove the night shift.
你们得保护他
You need to protect him.
地方检察官抓住Borger在证人席上犯的错误
The D.A. tripped Borger up on the stand,
让他承认了
got him to admit that Jack
Jack有暴力倾向 猜忌
was violent, jealous.
通过这个和验尸官的证词
Between that and the coroner's testimony,
陪审团决定判他有罪
the jury was ready to convict.
一级谋杀
Murder one.
毫无疑问
There's no doubt,
Jack Gordon谋杀了Ortega军士长
Jack Gordon murdered Petty Officer Ortega.
这是我的专业意见
That is my professional opinion,
也是我的个人观点
and it is my personal opinion.
反对 法官阁下 Wade医生
Objection, Your Honor. Dr. Wade is qualified
只有权做专家证言
only for expert testimony.
反对有效 请只回答...
Sustained. Please, just answer...
Ortega案子的庭审录像吗
Court footage of the Ortega case?
没错 1997年庭审法庭
Yeah. Circa court 1997.
只是说说 Wade医生看起来棒极了
Just saying, Dr. Wade looking mighty fine.
而且气炸了
And pissed, too.
是啊 那可不是一般的案子
Yeah. Wasn't an ordinary case.
可怕的谋杀
Horrendous murder.
很多情绪在里面
Lot of emotions.
是啊 没错 好医生Wade很少隐藏她的情绪
Yeah, well, the good Dr. Wade's barely hiding hers.
...通常是谋杀的前兆
...oftentimes is a precursor for murder.
反对
Objection.
你认为被告患有的
And you think the defendant's
精神疾病可能导致
mental illness could've made him
他具有极端暴力倾向吗
capable of extreme violence?
反对 她不是心理学家
Objection, she's not a psychologist.
-我允许继续发言 -我没杀她 我是无辜的
- I will allow it. - I didn't kill her! I'm innocent!
-法证不会撒谎 -我没杀人
- Forensics don't lie! - I didn't do it!
我没杀人 你知道我没杀人
I didn't do it, and you know I didn't do it!
Gordon先生 Gordon先生
Mr. Gordon, Mr. Gordon!
-我没杀她 -你没杀才怪
- I didn't kill her! - The hell you didn't!
我没杀人
I didn't do it!
-你知道这不是事实 -我没杀人
- You know that's not true! - I didn't do it!
你没杀才怪
The hell you didn't!
我的行为是不可原谅的
My behavior was inexcusable.
过去的事总会缠上你 对吧
The past has a way of catching up to you, doesn't it?
我不知道
I don't know.
总觉得我处理这件案子的时候
There's just something about this case
带有个人主观色彩
that I just personalized.
我应该从科学的角度
I was supposed to state the facts,
去阐述事实
as I knew them.
科学
The science.
而不是给出我认为无罪还是有罪的意见
Not give my opinion on innocent or guilt.
但Gordon有罪
Yet Gordon was guilty.
他认罪了也坦白了
He pled out, he confessed.
可是为什么
But why?
要么他真有罪
Was he really guilty,
要么因为我影响了陪审团没有客观看待事实
or did I sway the jury with something other than facts?
Loretta 你在过去的很多年里为无数案子做过证
Loretta, you've testified in dozens of cases over the years.
你为什么非要在这件案子上折磨自己呢
Why are you beating yourself up over this one?
你知道原因的 Dwayne
You know why, Dwayne.
你看到了庭审录像
You saw the courtroom footage.
那不是我原本的样子
I wasn't myself.
而且事后我一直都知道
And I've known it for a long time, too.
我只是从未想过去面对
I just never wanted to face it.
Jack和我一起长大
Jack and I grew up together.
我们一起上了高中并进入了运输局
We went to high school, joined the transit authority.
那时候 有轨电车来回都是同一个司机
Back then, streetcars only used one driver both ways.
我想你也认识Janet Ortega
I take it you knew Janet Ortega, too?
当然 她早上坐Jack开的电车上班
Well, sure. She rode Jack's streetcar to work
晚上坐我开的电车回家
on the early shift, mine back home at night.
基本上每天都能见到她
Saw her pretty much every day.
她和Jack在一起的时候挺好的
She and Jack were good together.
知道他害死了她
Until he killed her.
我仍然无法相信是他做的
Still can't believe he did it.
意思是 你觉得他是无辜的
Meaning, what? You think he was innocent?
那时候是的 我是说 我知道他有多爱她
At the time, yeah. I mean, I know how much he loved her.
Jack一生都忍受着
Jack struggled with paranoia and delusions
偏执与幻觉的折磨
his whole life.
我以为他的情况已经得到控制
I thought he had it under control.
当时地方检察官引导你在法庭上这么说的
Is that what the D.A. got you to say in court?
是的 这成了他定罪的依据
Yeah. It helped send him away.
好吧 他现在出狱了 若他为了报仇
Yeah, well, he's out now, and if he killed Karen Decker
杀了Karen Decker 那你也不安全
out of revenge, then you're not safe, either.
你能否帮我们想想
Is there any chance you might help us figure out
在哪儿能找到Gordon
where Gordon might be?
我是说 我们越快抓到他
I mean, the sooner we get him off the streets,
就能越早保障其他指正过他的人的人身安全
the sooner the people who testified against him are safe.
我觉得今天早些时候我看到Jack了
I think I saw Jack earlier today,
在车站对面的马路上
across the street from the station.
你当时为什么不报警
So, why didn't you call the police?
我当时不确定那是他
I wasn't sure it was him.
况且 我当时也不知道他又杀人了
Besides, I didn't know he'd just killed somebody else.
-好消息 -嗯
- Uh, good news. - Mm-hmm.
Christopher说所有指证过Gordon的人
Christopher says everyone who testified against Gordon,
都被警方保护了
under police protection.
很显然 我也是 拿着
Apparently, so am I. Here.
噢 对了 我睡觉不打呼
Oh, by the way. I don't snore.
至少就我所知 不打呼
At least, not that I know of, anymore.
我不知道我还打不打呼
I don't know if I do anymore.
你觉得我们其中的一个还会再婚吗
You think either of us will ever get married again?
噢 我自己倒是不着急 你呢
Oh, I'm not in any hurry, myself. You?
如果遇到对的人 也许会吧
If the right person came along, maybe.
前一段婚姻让我挺失望的
Last one kind of soured me on the idea.
是啊 不过也是很久以前的事了
Yeah. Long time ago, though.
就在Gordon的案子之前离的婚 对吗
Divorce happened just before Gordon's case, didn't it?
那是我搬到了这里的原因
That's the reason I moved here.
一个崭新的开始
New beginnings and all.
是啊 有许多要经历的
Yeah. A lot to go through.
Gordon的案子肯定让一切变得更加困难了
Gordon's case must've made it even harder.
我们这是要聊什么 Dwayne
Where are we going with all this, Dwayne?
没什么 只是
Not going anywhere, just...
我知道你丈夫对你不好 所以
I know that your husband didn't treat you right, either, so...
不 不是他对我不好
No, it isn't that he didn't treat me right.
你知道的 他疏远我了
You know it. He froze me out.
一开始他不是这样的
He wasn't like this at first,
自从他开始嫉妒我的成功
just started to resent my success.
事情变得越来越糟
Then it got even worse
当他被还不如他够格的人淘汰后
when they passed him over for others less qualified.
他开始变得刻薄
Then he got mean.
我用了很长时间 鼓起勇气离开他
It took a long time to find the courage to leave him,
但最终我做到了
but I finally did.
我算是幸运的
I was lucky.
比Janet Ortega幸运多了
Luckier than Janet Ortega.
你们都是受害者
You were both victims.
他们都是加害者
And they were both abusers.
但我当时依旧
But I was still
对于Reginald对待我的方式感到愤愤不平
so upset and so angry with how Reginald treated me,
所以我在作证的时候 我把一切都投射到了Gordon身上
that when I testify, I projected all that onto Gordon.
以及
And...
在那之后
ever since,
我一直很担心是我陪审团对他产生了偏见
I've worried that I biased the jury against him.
但这并不能改变对Gordon的指控
It doesn't change the fact that the evidence against Gordon
证据确凿
was overwhelming.
不只是你的证词
Wasn't just your testimony.
但我的证词确实产生了某些影响
But my testimony made an impact.
我能从每一个
I saw it in each
陪审团成员的脸上看出来
and every one of the juror's faces.
我当时并不是想让Gordon付出代价
I wasn't trying to make Gordon pay.
我是想让我的丈夫付出代价
I was trying to make my husband pay.
从此以后这事就挥之不去
And it's haunted me ever since.
Loretta
Loretta.
别动
Don't move,
冷静
and stay calm.
好吗
Okay?
- Gordon -嗯哼
- Gordon. - Mm-hmm.
在外面
Outside.
等一会儿 然后打911
Just wait a minute and call 911.
我去把毯子
I'm gonna go get this blanket,
枕头
pillows.
这些东西放到沙发上 我马上回来
Put them out on the sofa, I'll be right back.
噢
Oh!
-放开我 -冷静 Gordon
- Get off me! - Calm down, Gordon.
别反抗了 冷静点
Stop fighting. Relax.
冷静点
Relax.
别反抗了
Stop fighting.
Gordon 你因谋杀Karen Decker
You're under arrest, Gordon,
被捕了
for the murder of Karen Decker.
不是我做的
I didn't do it.
不是我干的
I didn't do it!
学校里的血不是我的
The blood at the school wasn't me!
你就是不明白
You just don't understand!
帮我理解一下 Gordon
Help me understand, Gordon,
你在Wade医生家外面干什么
what were you doing outside Dr. Wade's house.
我得吃药 把我的药拿来
I need my meds. Get me my meds!
我马上拿 你现在情绪激动
I'm getting them. The agitation you're feeling
是氯氮平缺乏引起的
right now is clozapine withdrawal.
你哪儿也别想去
You're not going anywhere.
试着呼吸
Try and breathe.
咽口水
Swallow.
谁在那儿
Who's there?
谁在那边
Who's on the other side of there?!
那里有人盯着我
There's somebody looking at me!
我知道有的
I know there is!
谁在那边
Who's on the other side?
Wade医生 是你么
Dr. Wade, is that you?
我不是去伤害你 我发誓
I wasn't gonna hurt you, I swear.
我只想让你帮我一把
I just wanted your help!
跟我说话啊
Talk to me.
Gordon 看着我
Gordon, look at me.
你说你想要她的帮助 是什么意思
What do you mean when you say you want her help?
什么帮助 药物么
For what, medication?
不 不是
No, no.
我只想要 我想要她
I just want... I wanted her!
我需要一个相信我的人
I need someone to believe me!
我没有杀害Janet
I didn't kill Janet!
我向上帝发誓
I swear to God.
我没有杀Janet
I didn't kill Janet!
如果Gordon没有杀害Janet Ortega
If Gordon didn't kill Janet Ortega,
他也就没有杀害Decker军士长
he didn't kill Chief Decker either.
好了 慢一点 行么
All right, slow down, okay?
他自称清白 不代表他就清白
Just 'cause he claims he's innocent, doesn't mean he is.
他是个绝望的人
He's a desperate man.
没错 但是他宣称自己的清白已经超过20年了
Yes, but he has been claiming his innocence for over 20 years.
无论是否有罪 我们都得确认
Guilty or not, we have to be sure.
给他点氯氮平
Gonna give him his clozapine,
等他安静下来再和他好好谈谈
then talk again after he settles down.
我们还是要一步步的来
We're gonna take this one step at a time,
就像我们一直以来一样
just like we always do.
也许我漏了点什么
Maybe there's something I missed.
或者是因为我希望他
Or maybe it was really because
是有罪的
I just wanted him to be guilty.
Loretta
Loretta...
我得查清楚 你也得查清楚
I need to check, you need to check.
因为如果Jack Gordon是无辜的
Because if Jack Gordon is innocent,
凶手就仍然逍遥法外
then the killer is still out there.
你想要我们中的谁和她一起 确保她的安全么
You want one of us to stay with her, make sure she's safe?
她没事的
She'll be okay.
凶手要么就锁在我们的审讯室里
Killer's either locked up in our interrogation room,
要么就认为他已经赢了这场游戏
or out there thinking he's won the game.
再开杀戒只会证明Gordon的清白
Killing again would just prove Gordon innocent.
你不会确定Gordon就是凶手吧
You're not convinced Gordon's our killer, are you?
我确定有可能
I'm convinced there's a possibility
他说的都是实话
he's telling the truth,
那我们就得继续调查
so we're gonna keep investigating.
我很尊敬医生
Well, all due respect to the doc,
但是要在20年间里
but somebody would be going through a lot of trouble
陷害Gordon两次
to set Gordon up twice
可是很麻烦的
across a span of 20 years.
我承认希望不大
I admit it's a stretch,
但是正如Loretta所说 我们需要确认
but like Loretta says, we need to be sure.
好 计划是什么
All right, what's the plan?
Loretta要复查一遍Janet Ortega的
Loretta's gonna review the forensic evidence
法医鉴定 确保不漏掉任何东西
on Janet Ortega, in case she missed anything.
要让当地警察掘出尸体
Gonna ask the D.A. to exhume the body.
也就是说 我要你去Morgan城
That means I need you to go to Morgan City,
把尸体带来 送到停尸房
pick it up and get it to the morgue.
明白
You got it.
你和Patton需要梳理一下
You and Patton need to comb through both
Ortega和Decker的谋杀案
Ortega's murder and Decker's.
看看能不能找出两者之间
See if you can find a connection to anybody else
除Gordon之外的联系
other than Gordon.
药片 King
Pills, King.
如果有人会用20年来
If somebody had 20 years
陷害Gordon是杀人犯
to frame Gordon for another murder,
那就很有可能没有犯任何错误
chances are they didn't make a mistake.
但是如果他们犯错了 我们就要找出来
But if they did, we need to find it.
这次我们需要绝对确认
We need to be right about this.
- 这是为了Gordon和Loretta - 好的
- Both for Gordon and Loretta. - Okay.
有人吗
Knock, knock.
没事 Sebastian 进来吧
It's okay, Sebastian, come in.
那就好 我不想再吓你一跳了
Okay, cool, I didn't want to scare you again.
上次真是吓到我了
Kind of freaked me out last time.
不是你的错 很明显
Not your fault, obviously.
就是个童年的症结
It's just childhood issues.
你懂的 暴躁的母亲
You know, jumpy mother.
我觉得我得去看看心理医生了
I'm thinking I should get into therapy...
-那是给我的 -对
- That for me? - It is.
抱歉 呃
Yeah, I'm sorry. Anyway, uh,
警察把Ortega的旧证据箱留给我了
the D.A. released Ortega's old case evidence from Property.
我们要找什么
What are we looking for?
说实话 我也不知道
Frankly, I'm not sure,
但我想确认我没有错过什么东西
but I want to be sure I didn't miss something.
我详细阅读了案件卷宗
I perused the case file.
我不觉得你漏了什么
I don't think you did.
我是说 每一处"我"都标注了
I mean, every “I” is dotted,
每个"他"都在法庭证裁决里打勾
every “T” is crossed on your forensic findings.
至少 你知道 依我看
At least, you know, to my eye.
不能过于自信 有很多事仍然不确定
Can never be too certain. There's too much at stake.
同时
Meanwhile...
你仔细看看这个
...you mind to take a closer look at this?
这是什么 你从Decker军士长
What is this, the hair sample you found
身上找到的头发样本么
on Chief Decker's body?
我已经确认这个是Gordon的头发了
I already identified it as Gordon's.
嗯 但是我们需要知道这究竟是从他身上掉下来的
Mm-hmm, but we need to know if it fell from his person,
还是被某人放在被害人身上的
or if it was placed on the victim by someone else.
你认为Gordon是被陷害的么
You think Gordon was set up?
做个碳酸钙测试吧 然后再看
Do a calcium carbonate test. Let's find out.
你现在可以给我解开手铐了 我不会伤害你的
You can uncuff me now. I ain't gonna hurt you.
呃 至少在药效过去之前吧
Well... at least till the meds wear off.
谢谢你
Thank you.
Jack Gordon
Jack Gordon...
20年前被认定杀害了Janet Ortega
pled guilty to killing Janet Ortega 20 years ago.
在你被释放一周之后
A week after your release,
此案的一位关键目击证人被
a key witness against you was murdered
同样的方式谋杀了
in the exact same way.
我为什么要相信你是无辜的
Why should I believe you're innocent?
因为我是清白的
Because I am innocent.
我从未停止证明自己清白 将来也不会
I never stopped trying to prove it, never will.
你为什么在假释期间给Decker军士长打电话
Why'd you call Chief Decker the moment you were paroled?
因为我需要她的帮助来证明我没有杀害Janet
Because I needed her help to prove I didn't kill Janet.
我说服了她我没有罪
I convinced her I wasn't guilty.
那就是20年前有人陷害你了
So, somebody set you up 20 years ago?
那人也在昨天陷害了你 你是这个意思么
Somebody set you up yesterday-- is that what you're saying?
我知道着看起来是怎样的
I know how this looks, okay?
我是被确诊的精神分裂症患者
I'm a diagnosed schizophrenic.
但你得相信我 我爱Janet
But you have to understand, I loved Janet.
她加入海军离开我时 差点让我崩溃
When she joined the Navy to get away, it nearly destroyed me.
谋杀工具 折刀
The murder weapon, the jackknife--
Jack的刀 是你的
Jack's knife-- belonged to you.
我为了保护Janet 把刀给了她
I gave Janet that knife for protection.
避免我伤害她
From me.
我有时会发疯
I got crazy at times.
当我神志不清时 我会伤害她 我知道
And I abused her when I wasn't in my right mind, I know.
但那也是我希望Janet能够
But that's why I wanted Janet to be able
保护自己 以防万一的原因
to protect herself in case.
她不得不离开我
She had to leave me.
我永远不会杀害她 Pride探员
I could never kill her, Agent Pride.
同样 我也不会杀害Karen Decker
Same way I could never kill Karen Decker.
Karen是唯一愿意帮助我的人
Karen was the only one willing to help me.
我为什么要杀她呢
Wh-Why would I?
先假设我会相信你
So let's say I believe you.
那是谁陷害了你
Who set you up?
你一定有些头绪
You must have some idea.
我只知道有人喜欢Janet
All I know is someone else liked Janet,
他们在追求她
and they was pursuing her.
肯定是杀害她的人
It had to be whoever killed her
还杀了Karen Decker
killed Karen Decker, too.
也许他们认为我们快要接近真相
And maybe they thought we was close
弄清楚他们是谁了
to figuring out who they was.
接近 怎么会
Close? How?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
昭雪计划-他们把
The Innocence Project-- they gave me
案件卷宗给了我 在我坐牢的时候
my case files while I was in prison.
好吧 我把文件都倒了出来 我什么都没有发现
Okay, I poured over the files, I didn't find anything...
直到我看到Janet的这张照片
till I found this one photo of Janet.
我最后一次见到她
Last time I saw her,
在她被杀前一个小时
an hour before she was killed,
她带着一条项链
she was wearing a necklace...
上面有紫色的宝石
with a purple gemstone...
但项链不是我给他的
but it wasn't from me.
-所以呢 -在她的尸体
- So? - So it wasn't
被发现时她也没有带着项链
on the body when she was found.
我看了所有的犯罪现场的照片
And I looked at every crime scene photo,
项链没在
and it wasn't there.
凶手拿了它 因为他知道
Killer took it. 'Cause he knew
通过项链能找到他
that it might connect back to him.
你可以自己查查这些照片
You could check the photos yourself,
你会发现我是对的
and you'll see I'm right.
你会发现我没有杀人
You'll see I didn't do this.
你发现什么了
You find something?
我想也许吧
I think maybe, yeah.
Gordon的头发上有微量的碳酸钙
Gordon's hair had trace amounts of calcium carbonate on it.
凶手使用橡胶手套把头发
Transferred from the latex gloves the killer used
放在Decker军士长的尸体上
to plant a hair on Chief Decker's body.
对的
Yeah.
这意味着如果Gordon没有杀害Decker军士长
Which means if Gordon didn't kill Chief Decker...
他可能也没有杀害Janet Ortega
he probably didn't kill Janet Ortega, either.
这也意味着
Which also means
一个无辜的人在监狱里度过了20年
an innocent man spent 20 years of his life in prison,
我的推波助澜送他进了监狱
and I helped send him there.
没别的了吗 与其他的凶案没有
Nothing else? No other connections
别的联系了吗 除了她们是如何被杀的之外
to the other murders other than how they were killed?
迄今为止我们什么也没找到
Nothing we can find so far
除了与Gordon的有明显联系外
other than the obvious connection to Gordon.
我觉得这太明显了
It's too obvious for my taste.
也太干净了
Too clean, too.
-是的 -如果Gordon没有做
- Yeah. - If Gordon didn't do it...
作案的人知道如何掩盖他们自己的踪迹
whoever did knew how to cover their tracks.
像是在海军或者执法机关的人
Like someone in the Navy or law enforcement--
但我们检查了受害人的档案
but we checked both victims' records,
-没有线索 -没有什么能证实
- nothing jumps out.  - Nothing to confirm
Gordon声称的Janet Ortega的神秘追求者吗
Gordon's claim of Janet Ortega's mystery suitor?
除了紫色的宝石项链以外 没有了
Nothing other than the purple gemstone necklace.
不管怎样 被害人
However, the victim was wearing it
在被杀前就戴着它 就像Gordon说的
right before she got killed, like Gordon said.
这是Decatur电车站的一台监控摄像机
This is from a surveillance camera
在那个晚上拍到的
at the Decatur streetcar station that same night,
20年前
20 years ago.
除此之外
Except,
在她被害以后
she wasn't wearing it
她没有戴着它
after she was killed,
就像Gordon说的
also like Gordon said.
好吧 这是合理的 对吧
Well, it makes sense, right?
凶手不希望任何人找到他
Killer doesn't want anybody tracing it back to him.
你知道吗 我开始觉得也许Gordon是对的
You know what? I'm starting to think maybe Gordon's right,
有人陷害了他
somebody's setting him up.
尤其是当凶案看起来越恐怖
Especially since the more grisly
越暴力
and violent the murders appear,
陪审团就越倾向于
the more a jury's predisposed to believe
虐待和精神疾病可能是起因
that abuse and mental illness could be the cause.
问题是 除了Gordon的观点
Problem is, other than Gordon's claim,
我们也没有什么来继续调查了
we don't have much, if anything, to go on.
但是我们查明是谁把项链给了Janet Ortega
But we find out who gave Janet Ortega that necklace,
我们就有东西查了
and we will.
才把尸体挖出来 花费的时间比预料的时间要长
Took 'em longer than they thought to dig it out,
地面仍然潮湿
that ground was still pretty damp.
幸运的是 把死者
Fortunately for us, burying the deceased
埋在泥炭沼泽附近的墓地里
in cemeteries near peatland marshes
可以防止尸体腐烂 分解
prevents putrefaction, decomposition.
你真的认为在过了这么久之后
You really think she can tell us something
她能告诉我们什么
after all this time?
时间可以治愈一切创伤
Time may heal all wounds,
但是 亲爱的 若是死了就治不了了
dear, but not when you're dead.
仍然很难相信
Still, it's hard to believe
只有你 遗漏了些东西
you, of all people, missed something.
是的 如果Jack Gordon是无罪的
Yes, well, if Jack Gordon is innocent,
那我肯定是有遗漏的
then I must have.
我现在回总部
I'm headed back to headquarters,
去帮他们找项链
to help them find that necklace.
有消息就告诉我
Keep me posted.
所以这些是
So these are
Ortega的原始尸检照片 -是的 呃
Ortega's original autopsy photos? - Yes, uh,
特别引人注意的是
this is the one of particular interest
她脖子的后面
of the back of her neck.
哦 某种擦伤
Oh, yeah, some kind of abrasion.
当时 我把它当作跟别的伤痕一样
At the time, I noted it as consistent with other wounds
可能是在她被拖进车里的时候
likely inflicted when she was dragged
造成的
to the car,
但在听了项链的事情后
but after hearing about the necklace...
这可能就是某人
It could be the wound was caused when someone
把项链从她脖子上扯掉后造成的伤口
ripped it off her neck.
如果是的话
If so,
这可能就是在我急于做出判断时
it could be what I missed...
造成的遗漏
in my rush to judgment.
Sebstian可能查到了些东西 说吧
Sebastian may have something. Go ahead.
好的
Right, well,
我们重新检查了Janet Ortega颈后一处伤口
we reexamined a cut on the back of Janet Ortega's neck
我们发现了微量的铂
and we found microscopic slivers of platinum
嵌在剩下的组织上
imbedded in what was left of the tissue.
如果凶手把项链从她的脖子上扯了下来
If the killer ripped the necklace off her neck...
小碎片可能嵌在了表皮下
Slivers might've gotten lodged beneath the skin.
这缩小了我们的搜索范围
That narrows our search.
太棒了 因为铂很昂贵
Big time, since platinum is pretty pricey.
嘿 Wade医生怎么样
Hey, how's Doc Wade holding up?
哦 你们懂的
Oh, you know.
她仍为此而深深自责
She's still beating herself up pretty bad over all this.
不能改变过去
Can't change the past.
但我们可以尽我们所能来
But we can do everything we can
让事情往正确的方向发展
to make things right moving forward.
我们会再和你联系 Sebastian
We'll get back to you, Sebastian.
嘿 我想我可能找到线索了
Hey, I think I may have a lead.
我一直在用图像软件
I've been runnin' the necklace from the Ortega photo
查找Ortega照片中的项链
through imaging software,
但我把范围缩小到铂金
but I just narrowed it down to platinum pieces only
砰
and bam!
运河街精品店设计并售出
Canal Street Boutique designed and sold
一样的铂金 钻石和紫水晶项链
the very same platinum, diamond and amethyst necklace
在1997年
in 1997.
如果我们能查到购买收据
If we can track down purchase receipts,
我们也许能找到
we might be able to find a suspect
在20年前和Ortega的生活有交集的嫌疑人
who intersected with Ortega's life 20 years ago.
疑犯不会很多
Can't be many.
4500 这么多钱
4,500 large.
案件会大逆转
That's some serious change.
看看这个
Check this out:
这家店位于
the store is located
Decatur有轨电车线路的尽头
at the end of the Decatur streetcar line.
那和Janet Ortega每天上班
That's the same street line
经过的街道线路一样
Janet Ortega took to work every day,
Jack Gordon在早上开车
with Jack Gordon driving in the morning.
他的伙计Todd Borger在晚上开车
And his buddy, Todd Borger, driving at night.
可能是巧合
Could be a coincidence.
但另一方面
but on the other hand...
若我们能把Borger和她的项链联系起来
If we connect Borger to her necklace,
我们就能把他和她的遇害联系起来
we can connect him to her murder.
还有一个问题 4500美元
Still, $4,500,
对于一个年轻的有轨电车司机来说太多了
pretty steep for a young streetcar driver
那个年头一个小时才赚
making, what, eight,
8到10美元
ten bucks an hour back then?
对于一个年轻的律师来讲不算高
Not too steep for a young lawyer.
珠宝店正好在
Jewelry store is right next to
Gordon的事务所隔壁
the office of Gordon's attorney.
对 Devon Mitchell 我们昨天到过那儿
Right, Devon Mitchell. We were there yesterday.
这意味着
Which means what?
Mitchell是把项链给Ortega的人么
Mitchell's the one who gave Ortega the necklace?
等等 Mitchell为什么要杀Janet Ortaga
Hold on, why would Mitchell kill Janet Ortega,
嫁祸Gordon
frame Gordon,
并且又转头为他辩护
and then turn around and defend him?
这是让Gordon败诉的最佳方法
Pretty good way to make sure Gordon loses the case.
如果Mitchell把Decker军士长也杀了
And if Mitchell killed Chief Decker, too,
那案件就肯定不会重审
make sure it didn't get reopened.
我们必须找到Mitchell
We need to find Mitchell.
Sebastian
Sebastian!
你本该让事情保持这样
Should've just let things be.
好 现在怎么做
All right, now what?
现在 现在你要把你服务器里的
Now? Now, you're gonna delete every piece of evidence
每一个证据删掉
from your server.
为什么 无论如何你还是会杀了我
Why? You're just gonna kill me anyway.
你背后的实验室技术员没看到我袭击了他
Well, your lab tech back there didn't see me hit him,
但是我也可以把他的眼珠挖出来
but I can always carve out his eyes, too.
快去
Go.
Jack向Decker军士长寻求帮助
Jack went to Chief Decker for help,
然后她来找你 不是么
and she came to you, didn't she?
快把文件删掉
Just delete the files.
只是好奇 你怎么知道我有证据
Just out of curiosity, how'd you know I had any evidence?
地方检察官给我打电话
D.A. called me,
告诉我你在检查Janet的尸体
told me you were exhuming Janet's body.
快点
Hurry up.
我忘了你们俩有多亲密
I forgot how chummy you two were.
很奇怪你没有
Surprised you didn't talk her
让她给Jack判死刑
into the death sentence for Jack.
是 鉴于他的情况
Yeah, well, the jury wouldn't buy premeditation
陪审团是不会相信他是早有预谋
because of his condition.
否则的话 我会让他被判死刑
Otherwise, I would have.
那又怎样
So, what,
只是因为
just because
Janet不会为了你离开Jack
Janet wouldn't leave Jack for you,
你就杀害一个无辜的女人 毁了一个男人的生活么
you kill an innocent woman, ruin a man's life,
之后又杀人么
then kill again?
没有你我也办不成这事儿 医生
Couldn't have done it without you, Doc.
你指证Jack的证据真是帮了我大忙
Your testimony against Jack really sealed the deal for me.
你怎么敢把Jack的事归咎于我
Don't you dare blame what happened to Jack on me.
-这全是因为你 -是
- This is all on you. - Yeah,
很不幸 对你而言
well, unfortunately for you,
你和我是唯一知道那件事的人
you and I are the only ones who know that.
不是吗
Aren't we?
Loretta
Loretta?
你还好吗
You all right?
-啊 -你还好吗
- Huh? - You good?
做的好
You did good.
请告诉我
Please tell me
一直被别人整
that getting my ass kicked all the time
只是做新人要经历的一部分
is just part of the whole newbie thing.
因为如果不是的话 我要很严肃地考虑
'Cause if it's not, I am seriously considering
重回实验室
going back to the lab.
还是买一堆生命保险
That or just buying a bunch of life insurance.
你的表现很不错 宝贝 你做的很好
You did great, baby, and you're doing great.
只是再坚持一下
Just hang in there.
她说的倒是简单
That's easy for her to say.
Gregorio多年来抓捕犯人 头破血流
Gregorio's been knocking heads and taking names for years.
是 她在New York长大 你知道么 而我是在Peoria
Yeah, she grew up in New York, you know? I'm from Peoria.
这儿 把它们敲回去 Peoria
Here, knock 'em back, Peoria.
Wade怎么样 今天早上有人去和她聊过么
How's Wade? Anyone talk to her yet this morning?
Pride去过 他说她已经好了很多
Pride has. He says she's doing much better.
-是 因为她也被耍了 -哦 别说了
- Yeah, 'cause she's kicking ass. -Oh, stop.
不比Lasalle好多少
Not better than Lasalle.
我听说Lothario又陷入了热恋
I heard Lothario's got himself another hot date.
他已经不再是
Oh, he's not
Lothario了
a Lothario anymore.
你的孩子都长大了
Your boy's all grown-up.
另外 这只是早餐
Besides, it's just breakfast.
请说明一下 你怎么什么都知道
And, pray tell, how come you know all of this?
你知道吗 一直给他一些提示
Well, you know, been giving him a few tips.
或是主动提供 但是他会听
Unsolicited, maybe, but he's listening.
组里有一个侧写师真是太方便了
Ah. Handy having a profiler on the team.
不是我自夸 但是我觉得我能识别出
Not being cocky here, but I think I pretty much identified
他的完美类型
his perfect type.
虽然还不太清楚怎么告诉他这件事
Not quite sure how to break it to him though.
-为什么是那样 -坚毅
- Why's that? - Tough,
忠诚 聪明 活跃
loyal, whip-smart, sassy,
可以陪伴男孩 得到多少就付出多少
can hang with the boys, and gives as good as she gets.
- Percy -Percy
-Percy?-Percy?
像我说的 还不清楚怎么告诉他这件事
Like I said, not quite sure how to break it to him.
你去哪里
Where you going?
我也要给自己找点儿药吃
I'm going to get me some pills, too.
想到他们在一起我就头疼
Just the thought of them together makes my head hurt.
我从来不会厌倦开着电车穿过城市
Never got tired of driving a streetcar through the city.
这是一份好工作
It's a great job.
爱工作的每一分钟
Loved every minute of it.
也许我可以帮点儿忙
Might be able to pull some strings,
看看我能否让你重拾工作
see if I can get you your-your job back.
你现在是自由的 Jack 除此之外 这个城市和政府
You're a free man now, Jack. Besides, the city and the state,
-欠你的不止这些 -可是
- they owe you more than that. - Still,
突然出狱并洗脱了罪名还是让我
it's a little scary being out all of a sudden,
有点害怕
cleared.
我花了这么多年尝试证明我的清白
I spent so many years trying to prove my innocence,
我都没怎么想 如果我成功了该去做什么
I didn't think much about what I'd do if I succeeded.
教习所可以帮你去适应
Well, the-the halfway house can help you adjust.
我也可以
So can I.
Wade医生也可以
So can Dr. Wade.
这就是你来见我 和我一起坐车的原因么
Is that why you wanted to meet, ride with me?
只是其中一个原因
One of the reasons.
听着
Look...
你向她寻求帮助
...you were right to...
是正确的
go to her for help.
现在也没有理由停止 Jack
There's no reason to stop now, Jack.
她为发生的事感到很难过
She feels bad about what happened,
比她应得的还难过
more than she deserves.
难过 天 她不是才帮我洗脱罪名了么
Bad? Hell, didn't she just help exonerate me?
而且 我从来没有怪过她
Anyway, I never held anything against her.
我的意思是 她什么都没有做错
I mean, she didn't do anything wrong.
我 我伤害了Janet
I... I hurt Janet.
而这事儿被用来反击我
Got used against me.
所有她做的只是说了出来
All she did was say it.
事实上
Actually,
或许是她最后救了我的命
she probably ended up saving my life,
因为我的情况让陪审团同情我
getting the jury to take pity on me 'cause of my condition.
那么你也有可能接受我来找你谈话的
Then maybe you'll be open to the other reason
另一个原因
I wanted to talk to you.
这个优秀的医生在无辜者计划中
The good doctor's donated her time
贡献了她多年的时间
to the Innocence Project for a lot of years.
你能否用你所了解的 去帮助其他遭受错误监禁的人
Could you use what you learned to help others wrongly imprisoned.
这也许会给你一些方向
Might give you some direction.
也许 能帮助你们两个有所恢复
Maybe... help the two of you heal a little bit.
有兴趣吗
Interested?
收藏么
Storage?
不 垃圾
No. Trash.
我不会再背负沉重的过去
I'm not gonna let the past weigh me down any longer.
是时候前进了
It's time to move on.
除非你想让我多聊聊我的前夫来烦你
Unless you want me to bore you with more talk of my ex-husband.
我要出去了
I'm out of here.
那正是我想要的
Mm, that's what I thought.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想进来喝杯茶么 Gordon先生
Would you like to come in for some tea, Mr. Gordon?
当然
Sure.